activation profiles. What the heck is an activation profile? I mean I know
those two words mean and I can kind of take a guess but between all of the
physical and logical and virtual and associations you know my head is still
spinning a little bit from all that IOCDS stuff. Maybe it's best we start with
some solid definitions. Now you're gonna hear me talking a lot about the CPC.
That stands for the central processor complex and it's the area of the main
frame where all the processors and memory live. Now the activation
profiles contain configuration information about the CPC and all of its
l-pars as well as information about the operating systems that we want to
run on them. That activation profile information gets stored on the
SE's the computers within the computer and when you use the HMC or the SE to
boot up or IPL and l-par it's going to read from the activation profile to see
exactly what it's supposed to do. I want to draw a clear distinction
between two terms that people often mix up. IPL and POR. An IPL is an initial
program load. It's what happens when an l-par gets its operating system loaded
into its memory, enough that it can start starting up. And a POR or power-on
reset is when the IOCDS gets loaded from the SE's into the hardware systems
area or HSA. And it creates all those logical paths we defined earlier. Doing a
POR means stopping everything that is currently running on all of the l-pars
and taking everything down. So PORs are typically something that is planned far in
advance to minimize the effect of that downtime. Now there are four types of
activation profiles. There's the reset profile. This determines how the
licensed internal code will be loaded and how much central and expanded
storage it will get. Then there's the image profile. Each l-par has an image
profile. This defines the l-par parameters like how many processes it'll get,
also how much memory it'll get. It'll also spell out if those processes are
dedicated to that l-par or if they're shared with others. Next up is the load
profile. This is needed to determine the channel addresses of the device that
the operating system is going to be loaded from. And then last up is the group
profile. This is a way of grouping objects so you don't have to change in
objects activation profile every time you want to activate it. These aren't
necessary but with a large number of objects, grouping can make managing them
slightly easier. During the activation of a reset activation profile, if the
mainframe is powered off, it'll begin powering up all of its components. Next,
the IOCDS gets loaded into the hardware storage area and all of those logical
definitions start getting made. It's coming to life here. The sub-channels, which the
l-par is used to communicate over those channels, start coming online, and we
start getting our l-pars and chippids and all the logical connections between
them. And that's all for the reset profile. Then the activation profile gets
loaded. And there's one of these for each l-par. This brings online the
processors and the storage to find for each l-par. And finally, we get to the
load profile. This means the l-par is starting to get its operating system and
it's coming online. It's ready to rock. So we've just gone all the way from P-O-R to
I-P-L. In the next section, we'll take a closer look at that I-P-L process. I know.
You're hoping I'd say that.